I wonder what's keeping Claire.
Relax. You'd better enjoy
your last moments as a bachelor.
Who are those people over there?
Oh, friends of hers, I think,
from that newspaper she worked on.
I wish she'd hurry up.
I'd like to get
the gang back to the newspaper.
Well, that's Claire for you.
Even late at her own wedding.
You know, I really hate to lose her.
What do you mean?
Well, I speak now as her editor,
not as a disappointed suitor.
Claire'd never make
a newspaper woman, and you know it.
Oh, I don't know.
She dug up more hot social stuff
than anyone The Tribune had had before.
That takes talent.
Nah, personality, Hank,
my boy, not talent.
All right, so
I appreciated her personality.
You appreciated it?
I was the one
that brought her to your attention
when she was only
an $18-a-week steno from a hick town.
Remember?
Very touching, Al.
You can put that in your memoirs.
She's marrying Hanneman now.
Listen to the frustrated lovers.
You know, if either of you guys
had made furnaces instead of small talk,
you might be in Hanneman's shoes now.
Have one of mine.
We do have memories, don't we, Les?
Carl Hanneman, wilt thou have
this woman to be thy wedded wife,
to live together according
to God's ordinance
in the holy estate of matrimony?
I will.
Claire Cummings,
wilt thou have this man
to be thy wedded husband,
to live together
according to God's ordinance
in the holy estate of matrimony?
I will.
I now pronounce you man and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
Congratulations!
Oh, you look breathtaking!
Thank you, darling.
- Oh, catch!
- Ooh!
Now June, don't tell me
I'm gonna lose another employee.
Don't worry, Mr. Doyle.
I don't even have a boyfriend.
We'd better go in now and cut the cake.
We'll have to hurry, darling,
if we expect to catch that plane.
I'll be right in.
I just wanna say my goodbyes
to a few of the gang.
All right, but hurry.
Thank you. Thank you.
Guess who?
Why did you come out here?
Because I love you.
Because you love me.
Claire, you, you're crazy.
Don't you know what
those words meant in there?
"Let no man put asunder"?
No one can put us asunder,
Les, you and me.
Oh, I never could figure you out.
Except that, well,
you make everything add up
to spell Claire, don't you?
- Now, darling.
- You're even getting
a sadistic kick out of
having me at your wedding,
me and the others.
But there are no others.
Only you.
I'll think about you on my honeymoon.
I'll write you.
Miss me, Les.
I know you both will be very happy.
- I beg your pardon.
- Thank you.
I'm ready with my cameras, Mr. Hanneman.
I've been looking for Mrs. Hanneman.
You haven't seen her, have you?
I believe you'll find her on the terrace.
Carl.
Why aren't you entertaining the guests?
I've been waiting for you, my dear.
I was detained.
On the terrace?
Don't you think
you were being a little affectionate
for a newly married woman?
Darling, you're
a great big old suspicious bear.
That was only Les Burns.
- And?
- It was nothing.
Just a friendly goodbye kiss.
Les did so much to help me
with my newspaper career.
Why, he's like a brother.
You're the only man for me, darling. Ever.
They're waiting for us.
Shall we cut the cake?
Come on, get moving!
One more!
- Come on!
- Pass him up!
Come on!
I win!
How much did he pay?
$10.80.
$10.80 for two. That's not bad.
I win 540 dollars.
Claire, you mean to say you bet
100 dollars on that horse to win?
Of course.
In these places, you have
to spend money to make money.
Let's see now.
I'll put 500 dollars in
the second race, High Heels.
- Come on.
- Wait, wait.
That's being foolish.
You're only out 100 dollars if I do lose.
It isn't the money.
It's the principle of the thing.
Principle? Carl, I don't understand you.
With all you have.
I've worked hard for what I have.
Oh, I don't mean to be a tightwad.
A little bet for fun is all right.
But I have too much respect for money
to throw it away on horses.
Of course, you're right.
It was foolish of me to bet so much.
Forgive me.
Of course.
Now, excuse me. I wanna go cash these in.
Hello, darling. Miss me?
Back so soon, Carl?
I only went to the barbershop.
Who're you writing to?
June Taylor. You remember.
Les Burns' secretary.
She was at our wedding.
Do you wanna read some of
the awful things I said about you?
It's hard for me to believe that I'm so
lucky as to have a woman like you
in love with me.
It's true, darling, every word of it.
Oh, sorry, Claire.
"My darling Les"? To June, eh?
Things are beginning to make sense now.
Carl, darling.
So that was a goodbye kiss
you gave Les Burns. Well?
Well, what do you want me to say?
Nothing.
There's nothing you can say, I guess.
I'm only glad I found out about it now.
Carl! What are you going to do?
I'm going back to San Francisco.
We're through.
But what am I going to do, Carl?
I don't care what you do.
But I have no money,
thanks to your great generosity.
That's enough for the week's hotel bill.
You've got that money from the racetrack.
Live on that.
You'll not get another cent from me.
Oh, no? I wouldn't be too sure of that.
I'm your wife, Carl.
There are community
property laws in this state.
It won't be that easy.
It'll be very easy when
I show this letter to the judge.
And I'm starting divorce
proceedings in the morning.
Oh, Carl, darling,
let's talk this thing over.
It's so silly.
Get out of my way, before I forget myself.
Would you please connect
me with the house physician?
Hello, Dr. Hastings?
This is Mrs. Carl Hanneman, bungalow nine.
Could you please leave a prescription
for some sleeping tablets
for me at the drugstore?
I'll be needing them right away.
I'm turning in early.
No. No, that won't be necessary.
I'm going out for a bite to eat,
and I'll pick them up later.
Thank you.
I want a new set of plugs in 42.
Okay, Blackie.
- Are you Mr. Talon?
- Yeah?
I must reach San Francisco by tonight.
I wanna be back by morning.
Can you make it?
I can make it up and back if, uh...
If what?
This weather holds out
and my fee is big enough.
How much will it cost?
Hm, 400 bucks.
Why five? I said four.
I know you said four.
I never made this trip.
You never saw me.
- Understand?
- Sure. Sure.
I don't even wanna know your name.
I'm glad we understand each other.
Perfectly.
Now, if you'll wait over there,
we'll be ready to leave in a few minutes.
Hey, Jack, roll out 41
and let's warm it up!
Right!
Room service, please.
Hello, this is
Mrs. Carl Hanneman, bungalow nine.
Would you please send
a waiter over with the menu?
Thank you.
Good morning, Mrs. Hanneman.
Good morning, Victor.
Let me see, I think
I'll take some orange juice
and, uh, toast, coffee.
That'll be all.
How was the ball game?
Ah, it was no ball game.
It was a track meet.
12 to nothing.
This all the mail today?
Yes.
By the way, I--I meant to ask you sooner,
but I'm going to have
a little dinner party tonight
for a couple I know.
You're invited if
you're not doing anything.
Well, sure. What's the occasion?
They're going to be married soon.
They're awfully nice kids.
Ah, married.
Then the trouble really starts.
Mr. Burns' office.
Long distance calling. It's Mrs. Hanneman.
Hello, Claire.
Hello, Les?
I'm so glad I caught you at the office.
How's the honeymoon?
It was interrupted.
Carl had to go back east yesterday.
Business, he said.
He wanted me to
stay over, wait for him here.
But I'm not. I'm coming
back to San Francisco tonight.
Do you think that's sensible?
Of course not. But I'll see you again.
Look, I want you to
arrange a plane ticket for me.
Reservations are so
hard to get at this end.
It'll be easy for you.
All right, Claire,
I'll take care of it tomorrow.
Tomorrow won't do.
I'm coming home tonight.
Okay, I'll wire you back on the time.
I knew you would help me.
Be sure and meet me at the airport.
I can hardly wait to see you.
Goodbye, Les.
Goodbye, Claire.
Uh, June, uh, get a hold of Hack Doyle.
Have him get me a reservation
on the eight o'clock plane
out of Los Angeles tonight.
It's for Mrs. Hanneman.
Are you planning to meet her?
Yeah.
Oh, I guess I'll have to
cancel our dinner party tonight.
It doesn't matter.
Apparently Claire
can get anything she wants
out of anybody at any time, can't she?
I never thought I'd be
back with you so soon, darling.
It's wonderful.
It's crazy.
Then why did you meet me?
I don't know.
I do.
Because you still love me, don't you, Les?
I'll get over it.
I hope Carl stays in
New York for a long, long time.
It seems a bit odd
he didn't arrange his business affairs
so they wouldn't
interfere with his honeymoon.
Yes, I thought so, too.
You certain you and
Hanneman didn't have some trouble?
What kind of trouble
could we possibly have had?
Quarrel of some kind. Perhaps over us.
Now, wouldn't that be ridiculous?
Giving him some reason to doubt me
so soon after we're married?
What do you think you're doing now?
You don't feel sorry for Carl, do you?
No. No, I don't.
But I should.
Look, let's forget all about him.
For a few days, anyway.
Take me home, I'll change,
and you can take me out to supper.
Claire, I'd--I'd rather not
go to the house.
But I--I must freshen up, darling.
I really must.
You want me to be beautiful, don't you?
Just for you?
You are beautiful.
See? There's nobody home.
Wait in there, darling.
I'll be down in a minute.
Come here.
Oh, darling.
Les, what is it?
Stay here!
Carl.
Suicide.
But why? Oh, poor Carl.
Claire, I thought
you said he'd gone to New York.
That's what he told me.
I don't understand it.
Why should he do such a terrible thing?
You probably know as
much about that as anyone.
It's gonna be one of
the first things the police ask you.
You can't stay here, darling.
I'll take you over to Hack Doyle's.
Where's your telephone?
Police headquarters, please.
I thought of you and
Hack right away, Mimi,
and brought her over here.
Hope you can put her up for tonight.
Oh, of course.
You can stay as long as you like, Claire.
Thank you, Mimi.
You're very kind.
It's just too incredible.
If he'd had any earthly reason.
We were so happy.
So very happy. And now...
- Oh, Hack?
- Mm-hmm?
Claire's going to
stay with us for a few days.
Oh, good. Plenty of room.
The police are over there now.
Murdock said he'd stop by here later.
You sure it was suicide?
Fairly sure.
But, a man in Hanneman's position?
A beautiful wife and all that money?
I don't get it.
I don't either.
Oh, hello, Bill. Come on in.
How are you, Hack?
Hello, Claire.
Hello, Bill.
Sorry this had to happen to you.
Sit down, captain.
How about a cup of coffee?
Thanks, Mrs. Doyle.
I won't annoy you for long, Claire.
Just a few questions. Routine.
- You know how it is.
- Of course.
Les gave me most of
the details over the phone.
Your husband, by the way,
has been dead for nearly 24 hours.
Uh, how did it happen
that Burns met you at the airport?
He didn't happen to.
I phoned him from Los Angeles.
How come?
Well, I was arriving late and alone.
I knew Les would pick me up.
Do you have any theory as to why
your husband came to San Francisco
after telling
you he was going to New York?
No.
I didn't know anything about the business.
The gun, of course, was Hanneman's.
We checked the serial number.
Funny, there were no
powder burns on the coat.
Bill, a suicide doesn't always
press a gun against his body.
In that case--
There would be no powder burns. I know.
Do you know of any reason why
your husband should have taken his life?
No, I don't.
Anything wrong with his health?
Not that I know of.
But that could have been the reason.
Had you quarreled?
Oh, no. No, we never quarreled.
Believe me.
Throughout every
minute of our married life,
we were supremely happy.
The entire week, huh?
Well, that's all for now.
I may wanna talk with you again later.
Where will you be?
- Right here with us.
- Thanks.
Uh, Bill?
- Yeah?
- You, uh,
found fingerprints on the gun, of course?
I mean, Hanneman's prints?
Uh-uh. Clean as a whistle.
Good morning, Les.
Just the guy I want to see.
Yeah? About what?
Oh, I've been assigned to do
the follow-up on the Hanneman case.
Oh? How'd you draw that?
Oh, I asked for it.
Be a dull job, because there isn't
gonna be any follow-up.
Just an ordinary suicide.
Are you kidding?
I never smelled an odor
of fish so strong in my life.
No fingerprints on the gun,
and you call it suicide.
So what? What makes you so sure?
Can you give me a good reason
- for Hanneman killing himself?
- No, I can't.
Perhaps he thought he had a good reason.
And perhaps he didn't.
So meanwhile,
if I can dig up a plausible motive--
Who asked you to dig up
a motive, plausible or otherwise?
I said, if I could dig up a motive,
I'm willing to accept suicide.
But if I can't,
then it'll have to be murder.
Still carrying
the torch for Claire, huh, Al?
Not anymore.
But somebody sure fixed it in a hurry
for you to get Claire again.
That's a nasty crack.
So meanwhile, chum, walk a straight line.
Or you'll have people
thinking you took a shot at Hanneman.
Why, you--
You've got a lot of work to do, Al.
You're so right, boss.
Sorry, Hack.
How's Claire taking it this morning?
I don't know,
she was still asleep when I left.
Les, I'm worried about this deal.
The police aren't
buying any suicide theory.
That why you put Herrick on the story?
Maybe.
He might dig up a suicide motive.
What's your slant?
Well, uh, Hanneman killed himself.
Nice try, Hack.
You're about as
subtle as a punch in the nose.
You think Hanneman
was murdered, don't you?
Maybe I'm protecting someone.
It's possible.
But I'd like to protect
someone if it isn't suicide.
- Like who?
- Like you.
Who had a better reason?
Hanneman's death
meant that you'd get Claire back
and a million-odd bucks.
That makes sense to
a lot of imaginative characters
around this town.
I don't believe it for one second.
But I still think it's safer
to sell the suicide theory,
if Herrick can dig it up.
Thanks, Hack.
But I didn't do it.
- Yeah?
- Sergeant Benson is here.
Send him in.
We're clear on the job?
Hello, Benson. What's on your mind?
The DA would like to
see you gents in the morning.
Says it's important.
About 10 o'clock.
What's he want us for?
Don't you know?
Oh, Mrs. Hanneman's
already got her invitation.
See you tomorrow.
You're certain, Mr. Burns,
that's the position you and
Mrs. Hanneman found her husband?
That's right.
One more question, Mr. Burns.
Your testimony at the coroner's inquest
said you touched nothing.
That's true.
Then how did you know the man was dead
without feeling his pulse or heart?
Mr. Chalmers, I've been around enough
to know a dead man when I see one,
especially after 20-some-odd hours.
You, uh, assumed
that Mr. Hanneman committed suicide.
Why?
Well, everything points to suicide.
Not in my assumption, Mr. Burns.
Mrs. Hanneman,
you say you saw your husband alive
on Monday afternoon.
And then the following night,
which was Tuesday,
you saw him again.
Yes, but he was dead.
I've told you everything.
You don't need a weather vane
to see which way this wind is blowing.
Was it customary for the servants
to take a vacation
whenever Mr. Hanneman left on a trip
and leave the house empty?
Well, I--I don't really know.
I--I didn't give orders to the servants.
Carl, Mr. Hanneman, ran the house.
I hadn't moved in yet.
I see that, uh, you also
assumed that this was a suicide.
Naturally.
It couldn't have been anything else.
That's what Mr. Burns said.
According to the Police
Scientific Detection Laboratory,
the pistol found near the body
was the one used in
the death of your husband.
But they found no powder burns
on the clothes of Mr. Hanneman,
nor fingerprints of
any description on the gun.
Furthermore, it is brought up
that Mr. Hanneman
couldn't have fired the gun,
because in making
certain tests of his hand
for traces of powder marks,
none was found.
Just what are you driving at?
Simply this.
Carl Hanneman was murdered.
But unfortunately,
I haven't enough evidence
to hold either of you.
You were out of town,
and your alibi was proven.
You're free to go.
But let me give you a tip.
I'm not buying any suicide theory.
So the case will remain open.
See you later, Ed.
So long, Hack.
Herrick really revels in pouring it on.
Well, it's news.
Nobody's been hurt. Yet.
"By person or persons unknown."
Could have been worse.
The DA certainly tried
hard to tag it on somebody.
Tell me, Hack, do you think that,
well, that Claire could have
shot her husband in some way?
No. She was in
Los Angeles the night he was killed.
DA couldn't shake that. And--
Good morning, everybody. I hope
I'm interrupting something important.
Hello, darling, you look tired.
Hello, Hack, dear.
Good morning, Claire.
This is a pleasant surprise.
What can I do for you?
I, uh, came to get my job back.
Starting when?
Now.
Well, after all that's happened,
don't you think
you should have a little rest?
Rest?
Why, working will be
the best thing in the world for me.
It'll keep me from
thinking too much about poor Carl.
After all, I must carry on.
My life is still ahead of me.
What's the real reason?
Well, I do need a little cash.
I have the house, and my clothes.
But I just won't be able to live
on the widow's compensation
the court'll allow me.
You wouldn't want me
to have to sell my clothes
in order to eat, would you?
Oh, no.
After all, I've--
I've made other arrangements
about your column.
Beth Warnock's taking it over.
You are still the boss, Hack.
Les, darling, wait outside for me.
I'll be out as soon as I've had
a heart-to-heart talk with Hack.
I know.
You might as well say yes, Hack.
I've had these heart-to-heart talks.
You will let me stay, won't you, Hack?
Yes, but I was hoping you wouldn't ask it.
You are a darling.
Listen, Claire, you stick to the job,
and no playing around.
There's enough trouble
here now without you adding to it.
I don't know why you talk like that.
I'm serious about it, Hack.
I'll work hard.
For your sake, I hope you do.
You are a dear.
See you later.
- Well, see you later, Al.
- All right.
Couple of your friends.
Yeah. Old friends.
Uh, two Martinis, please.
- Chicken salad?
- Fine.
Chicken salad for two.
And coffee.
Les, do you know a good lawyer?
Yeah, why?
Well, I need one to handle Carl's estate.
What's the matter with
Hanneman's regular lawyer?
Ugh, he's an old fuddy-duddy.
I want someone whom I can trust
to take care of my interests.
Well, you might try, uh, Lawrence Carson.
He specializes in probate work.
Carson. Good.
I'll call him tomorrow.
Do I know that man over there?
You should. It's Stanley Mason.
Our paper's backing him for Congress.
Of course.
Why, the pictures on his campaign posters
don't do him justice.
You know, I never could figure that guy.
Every time I see him,
he's with a different girl.
So?
Oh, we'll have four Manhattans.
Make them half French
and half Italian vermouth.
We'll order later.
I'll look after 'em personally, Mr. Mason.
Thank you.
Stanley, isn't that
that Hanneman woman over there?
Yes, she's very attractive, isn't she?
Well, if you like the type.
Why wouldn't he be
a good man to handle the estate?
No, no.
Nah, he's too tied up
with his election campaign.
What are his chances, Les?
On going to Washington?
Pretty good. Why?
That makes him important.
I've got to have someone with influence.
He looks like the kind of a man
who could get things done... quickly.
Capable enough, I suppose.
Probably make a good representative.
Personally, I just don't go for him.
I want you to introduce me to him.
You can do better.
Oh, darling, don't be stubborn.
I wanna meet him.
When you want something,
you want it right now, don't you?
You know what I really want, Les.
I know.
A fine old name like Hanneman,
a carload of dollars,
social position, the tops.
You're forgetting
the most important thing.
Am I?
You see, that's just the frame.
You're the picture in that frame.
What's that about a frame?
Sergeant Benson.
Won't you join us?
No, but Burns here can join me.
Been looking all over for you.
The captain wants to
have a little chat. Now.
What is this, a pinch?
No. Just an interview.
It won't take long.
It's too bad you couldn't have found me
at 10 o'clock this morning.
I was in a dentist's chair.
I'm sorry, Claire.
It's all right, darling.
I'll wait for you here.
Bye, Les.
Hello, Al.
Don't tell me
they finally grabbed Les for murder?
Wouldn't you like to hear me say yes?
Yes.
Well, don't stop the presses, yet.
You're the most composed dame I ever saw.
I don't believe you give a hoot
whether this case ever gets solved.
Oh, but of course I do.
Really.
Say, Al, how well do
you know Stanley Mason?
Oh, quite well.
I...I've planted some of his propaganda.
You can do me a favor, a big favor.
I wanna meet him.
Might be a good idea.
I remember I once
introduced you to a fellow
by the name of Les Burns,
and promptly lost you.
Excuse me.
Stan. How are you?
Well, hello, Al.
Say, I have a young lady
over here who'd like to meet you.
Just take a minute.
Well, all right.
Will you excuse me?
Of course.
Excuse us.
Claire, this is Stanley Mason.
Mrs. Hanneman.
I'm so glad to meet you, Mr. Mason.
How do you do, Mrs. Hanneman?
Won't you sit down?
Sorry I can stay but a minute.
I know you'll think me rather forward,
but being an attorney,
you can understand my predicament.
I'm desperately in need of someone
to administer my late husband's affairs.
I thought perhaps you could help me.
Well, I hadn't intended
on taking on any more work this summer.
My campaign requires so much attention.
However, uh,
supposing you come to my office
at, say, uh, four o'clock?
We can at least talk it over.
Oh, thank you.
I would appreciate it.
Here's the address. So long, until then.
Oh, excuse me. Sorry.
Thank you, Al.
Uh. Don't mention it.
I found him, Cap,
right where I expected,
with the grief-stricken widow.
Only if she's grief-stricken, I--
Skip it. Skip it.
Les, my boy, have a seat.
Last time it was, "Hello, Burns."
Today, it's "Les, my boy."
What do you want?
You know I just
wanted to chin a bit with you.
Oh? I didn't know I was that interesting.
Mm, you live out
in the Hanneman neighborhood, don't you?
No, and you know it.
But you go out
to that neighborhood
quite often, don't you?
Yeah, so what? To visit friends.
Oh, sure, that's right.
There's Hack Doyle and his wife.
June Taylor.
Say there's a clever little girl, huh?
Your secretary, huh?
Since when have you become
so interested in my secretary?
I thought
you were a happily married man.
Uh, weren't
you out in that neighborhood
the night Hanneman was shot?
- Monday night?
- Uh-huh.
No, I wasn't.
I played gin rummy with
the boys in the press room.
Went home to bed about 10 o'clock.
You read the testimony, did the checking.
Come on, Murdock,
what's on your so-called mind?
Funny, we can't find any record
of where you were between 10 o'clock
and eight the next morning,
when you had
breakfast at Drake's coffee shop.
Nobody saw
you around your apartment house.
Nothing so strange about that.
People in my neighborhood
mind their own business.
I spent the night sleeping.
You got an edgy temper today, Les.
Not worried about anything, are you?
I'm annoyed.
Until you and
the DA get this thing settled,
nobody'll get any rest.
We may have
the answer quicker than you think.
The police expect to
apprehend the criminal
within 24 hours.
Shall I quote that?
You can write out the gags, Burns.
You've been crazy about
Claire for a long time, haven't you?
That's right.
You thought she was gonna marry you.
Then she married Hanneman.
That must have been quite a jolt.
I won't deny that, either.
So you must have
been pretty sore at Hanneman
for beating your time.
All right, I suppose I was.
You know, Burns,
you've given out with all the motives
a man needs for killing another.
You don't need motives, Murdock.
You need evidence.
Evidence?
You just told me
that you were near the Hanneman home
last Monday night.
I wasn't.
Then how do you account
for your cigarette case
being found on the Hanneman garden,
still wet from Monday night's rain?
I don't have to account for anything.
But, to throw cold water
on your mastermind,
I tossed that away
right after the wedding.
Anything else you wanna know?
No. That's enough.
Next time, be more careful
when you talk to the captain.
Listen, Mr. Benson,
if I've hurt the captain's feelings
or yours, arrest me.
Then I can sue, and you'll be back
writing tickets for jaywalkers.
You rent that stool by the month?
Well, Lester.
Where's Claire?
Oh, Claire isn't here.
She had an appointment.
She go back to the paper?
No, about this time, she should be walking
into the inner sanctum of that courageous
and fearless champion
of the people's rights,
that distinguished candidate
for the Congress of these United States.
Um, Mr. Stanley Mason.
You sound like
you're on Stanley's payroll.
Mm-hmm. I introduced them.
You seem to have
a talent for that sort of thing.
Thank you.
I believe that's all the information
I need, Mrs. Hanneman.
I can't possibly find
words to express my gratitude
in your consenting to help me.
Oh, believe me, it's a pleasure.
A little pressure in the right places
should settle the matter quickly for you.
Thank you again,
and good luck in the elections.
Oh, thank you.
I suppose you'll be
leaving for Washington immediately
if you do win?
Yes. If I win.
You will. I know you will.
Well, I really must be going.
Well, can't I drop you off somewhere?
I'm sorry, not this evening.
Mr. Burns is taking me home.
He's the gentleman you saw me with today.
Well, I'll call you tomorrow,
and perhaps we can have dinner
and talk some more about your problems.
Splendid. Goodbye.
Look, Claire, don't
you think you ought to stay over
at Hack Doyle's a little longer?
It might be unpleasant.
Oh, don't be ridiculous.
Come on.
Oh, Roberts? Good evening.
Good evening, Mrs. Hanneman.
We weren't expecting you home.
We've made no arrangements for dinner.
I've had dinner.
Please take my bags to my room.
And you and Christine,
take the evening off.
- I shan't be needing you.
- Thank you.
Oh, and Mrs. Hanneman,
uh, I just wish to say,
on behalf of Christine and myself,
that we're pleased that you're home,
and we'll do everything
we can to make you happy.
Why, thank you, Roberts.
Well, come in, darling.
You aren't afraid of
Carl's ghost, are you?
You'll never be happy here, Claire.
Nonsense.
I've done a little refurnishing.
That oughta help a little.
Les, what did Murdock want with you?
He had an idea I might have paid
a visit here Monday night.
You didn't, did you?
Of course not.
It also seems I had a motive to kill Carl.
But of course you did,
if you were that kind of a person.
Murdock's only fishing.
Well, he knows I've been
in love with you for a long time.
I told him.
You told him?
Why not? It's true.
You want them to keep working on you
so they'll stay away from me.
That's it, isn't it?
Yeah, that's it.
I said I'd stand by you.
And you have.
And I love you the more for it.
You know I do love you,
don't you, darling?
I think you do, Claire.
In a peculiar, mixed-up sort of way.
I never should have married Carl.
I didn't really love him.
But he offered so much,
things I never had.
But that's all over now.
No, it's not all over.
And it won't be until
they find his murderer.
They will.
And there'll be nothing
to keep us apart again, ever.
Claire, if I could
only sell myself on that.
You've got to, Les. You've got to.
So that little tidbit
straight from the horse's mouth
brings us to the three-oh mark for today.
See you around about this time tomorrow.
Les Burns.
You're pretty sharp today.
That's the best column
you've done in two weeks.
Thanks.
If you say so, it must be all right.
- Hi, pal.
- Hello, Herrick.
Um, hear about your girlfriend?
They dragged her in this AM,
and Murdock and the DA
gave her quite a going-over.
No use charging to the rescue, Les.
Uh, Stanley Mason already beat you to it.
What'd they want with her, Al?
Well, it seems they had a hunch
Claire made a fast roundtrip into town
the night her hubby joined his ancestors.
Seems they thought her alibi
about being in LA
the whole time was the bunk.
Oh, that's ridiculous.
Oh, is it?
Well, you'd know
more about it than anyone.
June, put that through, please.
Okay, Al. You're so much
smarter than Murdock, spill it.
Oh, I'm not saying I am smarter.
But I do know Claire better than he does.
And I know you.
Meaning what?
Claire never lost
any interest in you before,
during, or after her marriage.
And that doesn't prove it happened.
With all that wampum at stake,
this whole thing could
have been planned weeks ago
by both of you.
I'm fed up with your dirty cracks.
Now get out!
Wait a minute.
Look, Junior, one of these days
I'm gonna be too late,
and you're not gonna have any teeth.
Mm-hmm. You're so right, boss.
What's wrong, Les?
Nothing. Forget it.
That's the way you want it.
If anybody wants me,
I've gone for the day.
Have one for me, too.
Where's Mrs. Hanneman? I gotta see her.
Is she in?
Why, yes, but she's going out.
This is important.
What's the trouble, Les?
Oh, I've been trying
to find you all afternoon.
You didn't go back to the paper.
Where were you?
I was with Stan, uh, Mr. Mason.
We were talking over the estate.
Oh. Looks like you got
some more talking to do.
It's really only business, Les.
Come in, but I can
only see you for a moment.
You've taken on quite
a package tonight, haven't you, Les?
Oh, I've had a few drinks.
Sitting over at Renard's
and thinking things.
- Crazy things.
- About me?
Yes, you.
Murdock and the DA
asking you all those questions.
It's nothing to be disturbed about.
I'm not so sure.
Why do you say that?
Were you in this room Monday night?
What? Why, you know I wasn't.
I don't know anything.
But I wouldn't lie to you.
Have I ever, Les?
Claire, there's only two people
who could've profited by Hanneman's death.
I'm one of them and you're the other.
Why, how dare you
come in here accusing me?
You only married Hanneman for this!
You've admitted it a dozen times.
But I didn't kill him.
How can you even think it?
- I didn't kill him.
- I didn't say you did!
But if you know anything,
you've got to tell me.
Were you in this room Monday night?
- No.
- You might have come in,
seen someone.
- I've got to know!
- Stop shaking me.
- Then tell me the truth!
- Let go of me!
I thought you were going to stand by me.
Why, you're drunk.
I'm only trying to help you and me.
Ha! Help me?
You're accusing me of murder.
How do I know you didn't kill him?
You were in town.
- Claire?
- I've as much right
to accuse as you have.
But I'm not accusing you.
Get out of this house.
I once said I couldn't figure you out.
I can now.
You're not a normal woman.
You're not warm.
You're cold, like ice.
Yeah, like ice.
Blonde ice.
Get out of here.
Oh! I thought it was--
Hello, Mrs. Hanneman.
I don't believe I know you.
Sure. Sure you do.
Let me come in.
We can talk better inside.
In there.
Now, what do you want?
Well, I saw your picture in the paper,
and I found out who you were.
I figured we could make a deal.
Deal?
I was gonna call on you last night,
but, uh, you, you had company.
And I had to see you alone.
What kind of a deal?
Seems that plane ride last Monday night
returned big dividends.
I paid you to forget me.
I thought I could trust you.
Sure. Sure, you can trust me.
But it's hard to forget
murder for any hundred bucks.
Why, you dirty double--
I don't like that word.
All right, we'll forget
what happened to Hanneman.
I'll go along with you
and that suicide story,
that is providing
there's a little consideration
of, let's say, uh, 50 grand?
50,000 dollars? Why,
I don't have that kind of money.
This estate's in probate.
I won't receive a thing for months.
I can wait.
But in the meantime,
I'll take this.
I know a little old man
who'll lend me money on it.
All right. All right.
Just don't come near this house again.
But I will keep in touch with you.
Quick, out the terrace door.
And don't forget, Mrs. Hanneman,
I'm not kidding about that 50 G.
I'll get it, Roberts.
Yes, ma'am.
Stanley, darling!
Thank you.
Well, he isn't at Renard's, either.
Oh, I hope nothing's happened to him.
He'll turn up when he runs down
or runs out of dough for drinks.
Say, uh, you write
his column all by yourself?
Somebody had to do it.
I hope it's fit to print.
It's good.
Nice of you to cover for him, too.
Do you really think he's all right?
Sure, sure. I'll find him later.
Don't worry about Les.
He's probably getting
more poison out of his system
than he is into it.
I hope.
Oh, hello, June.
See if you can get me
another head, will you?
This one's not gonna do me much good.
You certainly had
a little trip for yourself.
Ah, I guess so.
What day is it?
Tuesday.
Holy mackerel.
What happened to Sunday and Monday?
I took care of them for you.
You would.
Who found me, Hack Doyle?
No. Claire.
- Claire?
- Mm-hmm.
You were trying to convince the doorman
at the Top of the Mark
to let you out on the roof.
It was the only way to the moon.
Oh, brother. The moon?
Looks like I wanted
more than a little trip.
Here, drink this.
It'll make you feel better.
Guess I've been the horrible example, huh?
You no doubt thought you had a big reason
for getting tight.
I had to get away from something.
Something that wasn't good for me.
Uh, have any luck?
I don't know.
But, I'm never going through this again.
I can assure you of that.
June?
All right.
I guess I'd better get back to the office.
Thanks a lot for looking after me, June.
I--I'll be down after
a while, if I can make it.
Don't hurry.
Les? I wonder
which hangover you'll recover from first.
I thought we were all washed up, Claire.
Les, for everything
I said the other night,
I'm terribly sorry.
I guess I was a little mixed up myself.
Forgive me, darling.
I must have been out of my mind
to say such awful things to you.
I realized the truth later.
You were afraid for me
because you love me.
That was it, wasn't it?
Yeah, maybe it was.
I just couldn't believe that...
Look, let's forget all about it.
We know there's nothing to worry about.
There never was.
We know that, don't we, Les?
Sure, Claire. Sure.
Here's to our new congressman.
May your career be long and successful.
Thank you, darling. Geoff.
But aren't you both a bit early?
I only wish I could be as
sure of my future in psychiatry
as you can be of
your future in Washington.
Doctor, you were analyzing me at dinner,
the workings of my mind.
Do go on. It's very interesting.
I've never been psychoanalyzed before,
and your deductions amaze me.
Claire, I warn you, if Geoff continues,
he'll have you convinced
you're batty,
simply because your father
ran away with another woman
and your mother was
relegated to hard work.
Stanley doesn't quite believe
in the powers of
psychoanalysis, Mrs. Hanneman.
But if either of
you could spend a day in my office
listening to some of my patients,
you'd see the logic of my deductions.
Or any psychiatrist's, for that matter.
Oh, don't mind
Stanley's cynicisms, doctor.
- Yes, Roberts?
- Telephone for Mr. Mason.
- Excuse me.
- Certainly.
I was telling you at dinner
that I believe that money,
clothes, adulation, et cetera,
was a necessity with you,
that some people are
impelled towards an objective
without even consciously knowing why.
Is there something
criminal in my being ambitious?
Why, no.
Criminal? Of course not.
Unless your ambitions
take a perverse form.
Then you'll stop at nothing,
right or wrong,
to get what you want.
They say the female of the species
is deadlier than the male.
Go on, doctor.
Sorry to interrupt, darling.
It was my campaign manager.
He arranged a last-minute
radio interview for tonight.
I...I'll have to leave.
Uh, you can drop me off downtown, Stanley.
I'll get my coat.
All right.
Will you forgive me, darling?
Of course, honey.
I'm so proud of you.
Oh, I almost forgot the good news.
I had lunch with the DA this noon.
It looks like Hanneman's murder's
gonna be filed away under crimes unsolved.
It, uh, is their opinion
that it must have been done by a burglar.
Oh, I'm so glad, really.
Now I'll be able to go
with you to Washington
with a clear conscience.
Say, you haven't told any of your friends
about our plans, have you?
Oh, no, of course not.
Good. We'll surprise them tomorrow night.
Yes, we certainly will.
Ready?
Yes, thank you.
- Good night, Claire.
- Good night.
Uh, Mrs. Hanneman, please don't take
my mental probing too seriously.
You're a very charming hostess.
So don't worry.
I never worry. Good night.
Good night.
Hello? Yes, this is Mrs. Hanneman.
That's all right, Roberts. I'll take it.
Hello? Who?
How dare you call me here?
I had to. I'm in a jam.
I need some dough,
and you've got to help me.
The estate isn't settled yet.
I told you I don't have any money.
Don't give me that.
You're a smart girl.
If you haven't got it,
you know where you can find it.
I need at least a couple
of grand now and tonight,
or else I go to the cops.
I got nothing to lose.
I have about 700 cash and my jewelry.
All right, bring it along.
Meet me at the end of the Old Valley Road.
Be there in 20 minutes.
Did anybody follow you?
No.
Then stop being nervous.
I'm not nervous. You are.
All right, give me the stuff
and let's see if I can use it.
These look all right.
I got into
the bookies for a couple of grand.
They're bad little men,
and I've been stalling.
Tonight they told me, "Pay off or else."
They wouldn't kill you for 2,000 dollars.
They'd kill for a lot less.
That's why I had to put the bite on you.
Thanks, Mrs. Hanneman.
I wouldn't double-cross anybody,
at least not unless I had to.
I wouldn't
double-cross anybody either, Blackie,
unless I had to.
The first returns have been received
from the 12th precinct.
Mason, 311, Jeffers, 282, and Allen, 91.
That just about cinches it.
If I can do that well on the 10th,
I can carry them all.
My gratitude, Doyle.
Without your paper in back of me,
I wouldn't have had a chance.
Think nothing of it, Mr. Mason.
We're glad we backed the right man.
Well, it looks like you're in, Mr. Mason.
Congratulations.
Seen Les and Claire yet tonight?
No. I guess she's waiting
to make her grand entrance.
That's about 100 times
you've asked for them, Hack.
What gives?
Oh, nothing.
Mr. Doyle.
Looks like we have a new congressman.
Yes, it does.
I'm sure he's going to be a good one.
I hope so. We backed him.
Hello, Claire. Hiya, Les.
Hi, Hack.
Well, good evening, Claire.
You look stunning, as usual.
- Thank you, Stanley.
- Oh, hello, Les.
Thanks for bringing Claire for me.
- ...the 18th precinct.
- Oh, big night, huh?
In third place is Jeffers with 162,
Allen with 142, and Mason 300 even.
That's how big it is.
Come on, Claire,
I want you to meet some folks.
You'll find drinks in there.
Look, Les, there's something on my mind.
I wanna tell you about it.
Uh, you better have a drink first.
Sure.
Hi, folks, how's the brawl?
Well, at least the liquor's good.
Oh, Junie, aren't
you a pretty thing tonight?
Well, it's about time you noticed me.
The trouble with
you men is you always have ink
in your eyes down at the office.
Have a fresh one?
No, thank you. This will do.
Les.
Can I talk to you for a minute?
Excuse us.
- What gives?
- Uh, did you come with Claire tonight?
No. No, I came with my
Aunt Martha from Penobscot.
No, I'm serious.
You saw her come in with me.
You better get her out of
your system, but right now.
What are you talking about?
Things are fine with us now.
She couldn't be sweeter.
You should've seen her earlier,
helping me get things ready
for that little party
up at my place tonight.
How about a speech, Mr. Mason?
We haven't had one.
Come on, Stanley.
Yeah, give us a speech.
That's all I need.
Now wait a minute.
Speech? All right.
If you want a speech, you shall have it.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I want to introduce to you
a very lovely young woman,
better known to you as Claire Cummings.
I am happy to announce
that she's bestowed upon me
the great honor of
consenting to become my wife.
That was a dirty, low-down trick,
but I'm glad it's happened.
Someday I'll tell you why.
All the happiness in the world, my dear.
That was quite a speech you made, Stanley.
Surprised, Geoffrey?
Aren't you going to
congratulate us, doctor?
It's customary.
Hate to take you away
at this moment, Stanley,
but there's something
I must talk to you about.
It's important.
But of course, Geoffrey.
Will you excuse us?
I know you'll enjoy living in Washington.
When do you plan to have the wedding?
Don't look at me like that, darling.
And what are you doing here?
I wanted to see you alone.
Sure, not a husband
in sight, dead or alive.
I didn't have a chance to explain.
"No one can put us asunder,
Les, you and me."
It was more effective last time
with wedding music, remember?
Oh, you're cruel.
I didn't mean to hurt you,
and you are hurt, aren't you?
That's how much you bother me now.
Not a quiver.
What about your heart?
Claire Cummings Hanneman Mason.
Why, if this keeps up, you won't be able
to get your initials on your silverware.
I can't help it, Les.
I do love you, but you could never give me
the things I must have.
Money, importance,
with me, they're a necessity.
Oh, stop it, Claire.
You're like a poison.
Take a little bit and you're finished.
But too much becomes an antidote.
All right, darling.
But if we've really come to the end...
Stanley!
You mind, Burns?
I'd like to say
something to my fiancée alone.
Not at all, Mr. Mason.
Not at all. Go right ahead.
Congratulations are hardly over
before I find you in
the arms of your old sweetheart.
That was a stupid remark.
I had to say something to him, didn't I?
So you didn't tell him earlier.
You said you were going to.
Well, I--I couldn't find the words.
Is that why you're angry?
Oh, darling, let's not quarrel.
We can do that after we're married.
There isn't going to be any marriage.
What are you saying?
I'm afraid we've made a mistake.
You can't mean that.
What'll my friends think?
I couldn't stand the humiliation.
Oh, you'll get over it quickly enough,
as quickly as you did your other marriage.
Why are you talking this way?
What did that phony doctor tell you?
That's not important.
We've made a mistake.
Now, let's forget it, shall we?
But you can't throw me over.
I've looked forward. I've planned.
You're taking me to Washington with you,
away from these people, these memories.
I've got to go with you, Stanley.
No, I'm sorry. It's final.
You ought to see a doctor, Claire,
a doctor like Geoff.
I looked for you at
the party after he talked to me.
I merely wanted to ask you something.
Doyle told me where I'd find you,
but I didn't believe him, either.
But finding you here proves many things.
You're not well, Claire.
I'm all right.
I didn't mean to crack up.
At least we could have
a farewell drink together.
No hard feelings, really.
Why don't you fix some for us?
I must say,
you're being regular about it.
Claire!
What have you done?
I did nothing.
You killed him, Les.
I killed him?
Don't you remember?
You came in just a few minutes ago.
You saw us talking.
You looked funny, crazy.
You said you were going to kill Stanley
because he stole me from you.
So you picked up the knife
and you...you stabbed him.
You're out of your mind.
No, I'm not.
- You're insane.
- No.
No, I saw you do it.
You dropped the knife,
and you ran out the door.
I tried to stop you.
Came in just a few
minutes later, right now.
You murdering little idiot.
- Les, don't!
- Mason, you've won!
Allen just conceded the election.
You're going to--
You made it on the committee,
right there--
So you see, doctor, the evidence
is really stacked against Les Burns.
I and the others feel
that he's absolutely innocent.
Now I asked you down here
to see if there wasn't
something you could do
to help us prove Les is
innocent and Claire is guilty.
Because just as sure
as my name is Hack Doyle,
she's framed him.
I agree with you 100 percent.
I am positive
that Mrs. Hanneman killed Stanley.
But because of her testimony,
and finding the knife
in Les's hand when
you arrived at the scene,
the police could
come to only one conclusion.
Surely there's
something you can do to help him.
He's innocent. I know he is.
Look, you were once connected
with a big city police department.
Then you must have
run across cases of this sort.
I know now that Claire Cummings
is a nut if I ever saw one.
Yes, you're right, Mr. Herrick.
I'll at least have a try at it.
I'm just as interested in
finding Stanley's murderer
as you are in
proving Mr. Burns's innocence.
Now I have a plan
that might break her down.
Well, good morning, Dr. Klippinger.
To what do I owe
the pleasure of this visit?
It's no pleasure for me,
Mrs. Hanneman, I assure you.
I just came to ask one question.
Why did you kill Stanley Mason?
What?
How ridiculous you are, doctor.
Am I?
You see, I had a talk
with Stanley last night
concerning your betrothal
and advised him against it.
It's safe to assume
that when he came to tell you
that there wouldn't be any marriage,
you killed him in a fit of anger,
and then concocted
a story to implicate Mr. Burns.
That's the most absurd accusation
I ever heard.
You seem to forget
that Les Burns' fingerprints
were found on the knife,
and that he was seen
standing with it in his hand.
The police have all the facts, doctor.
Not all of them.
All they need to convict Les Burns.
Do you mind if I finish my column?
No. Why, no.
I suppose you'll tell
the police I killed Stanley
and give them that fantastic story
to back up your accusations.
It won't sound so
fantastic to them, Mrs. Hanneman.
I discovered one or
two other flaws in your story.
They'll laugh at you.
It's insane. Absurd.
Oh, you're wrong.
You see, I've spent my life
delving into distorted minds like yours.
I worked for the police for many years
as a consulting psychiatrist.
You sound more like a hypnotist.
And I'm quite fed up
with your insane theories.
Now, doctor.
Looking for something, Hack?
The police are on their way.
The police?
What for?
I see the three of
you dreamed this one up.
Well, as long as you're
going to have me arrested,
you might as well read my last column.
Go ahead, read it, Hack.
Read it out loud.
"I killed Stanley Mason.
I killed Carl Hanneman.
I killed Blackie Talon.”
You didn't know about Blackie, did you?
You hid that story on page five.
"Unsolved robbery and slaying."
"I killed Stanley Mason because--"
"...he no longer wanted to marry me."
Stanley Mason was
the top of the ladder for me,
the top rung.
I had money, and now
I was gonna have position.
He was taking me to Washington with him.
I could leave then without
making the police suspicious.
Clever of me, wasn't it?
Why did you frame Les Burns?
Why? Because he caught me
with blood on my hands.
Because at last, even he had discarded me.
I never loved any of them.
You, Al. Hanneman, Mason.
But Les, I wanted to hang onto him.
He was of no use to me,
but I couldn't let him go.
Maybe I did love him.
Hello? Miss Cummings?
No, she's out.
I'm glad you confessed, because you never
could have gotten
away with it much longer.
I would have, but for you, Dr. Klippinger.
You and your slimy scientific snooping.
As soon as you came in,
I realized it was you
who turned Stanley Mason against me.
You sent him to
his death just as much as I.
Sit down, Claire.
Why, but for you,
I'd have everything I ever wanted in life.
I hated you because you were the first man
who ever saw inside my mind.
And I'm gonna kill you.
Let go of my arm!
You were a little late, Murdock.
Well, it was probably better this way.
I can scarcely believe it,
a woman as beautiful as that.
You didn't know her very well.
None of us really knew her very well.
She wasn't even a good newspaperwoman.